Then we have another oblong brush.
Again, it's the wooden variety.
It's in a padded base as well.
This is a shorter brush, so it's shorter than the other oblong I was showing you.
This is a great brush if you're just showing your dog and you need to take a brush into the ring.
This is smaller.
This is a great brush to take into the ring with you.
This is also a nice brush to work on a small breed dog.
Again, we're using an example here of a large breed dog.
We're still working on pin brush with a large breed dog.
A large pin brush isn't a problem, but this might be a large brush if we're working on a havanais or a yorkie.
So if this comfortably in your hand, remember that the handle is going to be shorter as well.
You can see that here, but if this fits comfortably in your hand, this is a nice brush to use on a smaller breed dog.
How do you use a pin brush on a long coated dog.
Pin brush is a great finishing type of brush.
It goes right over, nicely over the coat.
It's not a really tough brush.
It doesn't pull out a lot of hair; you can see there's not a lot of hair.
It's really better to be used as a finishing brush.
It is not a good brush to take mats out.
So if you're trying to get undercoat out and trying to take mats out, this is not the brush you would want to use.
You would wind up bending the pins and pulling them out.
This is a brush you would use after you've gone over the entire dog with your slicker type brush and then you would use your pin brush as a finishing type brush.